<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://urszuladeger.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://urszuladeger.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-06-28T14:06:51+00:00</updated><id>https://urszuladeger.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Personal website </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Routledge book is out!</title><link href="https://urszuladeger.github.io/blog/2024/routledge-book-is-out/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Routledge book is out!"/><published>2024-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://urszuladeger.github.io/blog/2024/routledge-book-is-out</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://urszuladeger.github.io/blog/2024/routledge-book-is-out/"><![CDATA[<p>It’s been a while since I last posted, and quite a lot of things have happened. One thing is the publication of my book, “Digital Humanities and Laboratories: Perspectives on Knowledge, Infrastructure and Culture” by Routledge at the beginning of this year. You can find out more about the book at the <a href="https://www.routledge.com/Digital-Humanities-and-Laboratories-Perspectives-on-Knowledge-Infrastructure-and-Culture/Pawlicka-Deger-Thomson/p/book/9781032027630">Routledge website</a>. In short, it aims to explore laboratories dedicated to the study of digital humanities (DH) in a global context and contribute to the expanding body of knowledge about situated DH knowledge production. I’m proud of this book and honoured to have a foreword by Prof. David Berry. The book features contributions from a diverse, international range of scholars and practitioners. Some chapters are available on an open-access basis, including an introduction by Christopher Thomson and me. So please check them out here: https://www.taylorfrancis.com/books/edit/10.4324/9781003185932/digital-humanities-laboratories-christopher-thomson-urszula-pawlicka-deger</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s been a while since I last posted, and quite a lot of things have happened. One thing is the publication of my book, “Digital Humanities and Laboratories: Perspectives on Knowledge, Infrastructure and Culture” by Routledge at the beginning of this year. You can find out more about the book at the Routledge website. In short, it aims to explore laboratories dedicated to the study of digital humanities (DH) in a global context and contribute to the expanding body of knowledge about situated DH knowledge production. I’m proud of this book and honoured to have a foreword by Prof. David Berry. The book features contributions from a diverse, international range of scholars and practitioners. Some chapters are available on an open-access basis, including an introduction by Christopher Thomson and me. So please check them out here: https://www.taylorfrancis.com/books/edit/10.4324/9781003185932/digital-humanities-laboratories-christopher-thomson-urszula-pawlicka-deger]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Special issue on critical technical practices</title><link href="https://urszuladeger.github.io/blog/2024/special-issue-on-critical-technical-practices/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Special issue on critical technical practices"/><published>2024-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://urszuladeger.github.io/blog/2024/special-issue-on-critical-technical-practices</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://urszuladeger.github.io/blog/2024/special-issue-on-critical-technical-practices/"><![CDATA[<p>The long-awaited special issue on critical technical practices in digital research and beyond has been published in the <a href="https://publicdatalab.org/projects/pluralising-critical-technical-practices/">Convergence journal</a>. I’m pleased to contribute to this issue with an article on the critical study of documents produced in digital research production. I propose using the method of the “STS of documents” to analyse feasibility documents that aim to assess technical and design requirements based on research questions and to organise a project workflow. It is an open-access publication, so you can find it here: <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/13548565221111073">https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/13548565221111073</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The long-awaited special issue on critical technical practices in digital research and beyond has been published in the Convergence journal. I’m pleased to contribute to this issue with an article on the critical study of documents produced in digital research production. I propose using the method of the “STS of documents” to analyse feasibility documents that aim to assess technical and design requirements based on research questions and to organise a project workflow. It is an open-access publication, so you can find it here: https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/13548565221111073]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wellcome Calls for Proposals!</title><link href="https://urszuladeger.github.io/blog/2024/wellcome-calls-for-proposals/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wellcome Calls for Proposals!"/><published>2024-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://urszuladeger.github.io/blog/2024/wellcome-calls-for-proposals</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://urszuladeger.github.io/blog/2024/wellcome-calls-for-proposals/"><![CDATA[<p>I’m excited to share two requests for proposals (RfP) that have been published on the <a href="https://wellcome.org/what-we-do/our-work/contract-opportunities">Wellcome Contract opportunities website</a>. Under “Discovery Research” section, you can check out two calls for proposals to conduct landscaping work into the use of archive, manuscript, and material culture resources, as well as new forms of social data resources for life, health, and wellbeing discovery research across humanities and social sciences. We aim to commission a supplier or group of suppliers for up to a 6-month contract to produce a comprehensive report that will address the following objectives, such as understanding the challenges/barriers to be tackled in order to significantly enhance approaches to using these resources in research in the UK and globally; detailing the approaches, capabilities, technologies and data that could contribute to solving the challenges/barriers to maximise this research; and defining the opportunities for transformative life, health and wellbeing research that would be enabled by working towards the goal of significantly enhancing approaches to using these resources and data. The deadline for submitting proposals for each RfP is 25 July 2024.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m excited to share two requests for proposals (RfP) that have been published on the Wellcome Contract opportunities website. Under “Discovery Research” section, you can check out two calls for proposals to conduct landscaping work into the use of archive, manuscript, and material culture resources, as well as new forms of social data resources for life, health, and wellbeing discovery research across humanities and social sciences. We aim to commission a supplier or group of suppliers for up to a 6-month contract to produce a comprehensive report that will address the following objectives, such as understanding the challenges/barriers to be tackled in order to significantly enhance approaches to using these resources in research in the UK and globally; detailing the approaches, capabilities, technologies and data that could contribute to solving the challenges/barriers to maximise this research; and defining the opportunities for transformative life, health and wellbeing research that would be enabled by working towards the goal of significantly enhancing approaches to using these resources and data. The deadline for submitting proposals for each RfP is 25 July 2024.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chinese translation</title><link href="https://urszuladeger.github.io/blog/2023/chinese-translation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chinese translation"/><published>2023-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://urszuladeger.github.io/blog/2023/chinese-translation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://urszuladeger.github.io/blog/2023/chinese-translation/"><![CDATA[<p>I’m happy to share that my article <a href="https://academic.oup.com/dsh/article/37/2/534/6372159">“Infrastructuring digital humanities: On relational infrastructure and global reconfiguration of the field”</a> published in <a href="https://academic.oup.com/dsh">Digital Scholarship in the Humanities</a> has been translated into Chinese and released in the <a href="http://dhr.ruc.edu.cn/EN/2096-9155/current.shtml">Digital Humanities Research</a> journal.</p> <p>The journal is published by the Research Center for Digital Humanities of RUC, a leading research institution in the field of digital humanities in China, which is based at Renmin University of China. Its mission is to promote the development of digital humanities research based on the international academic frontier, build a platform for academic exchange, and promote the integration of humanities and science and technology.</p> <p>The translation has been made by Jianan Guo from the Research Center for Digital Humanities of RUC. I hope the Chinese-speaking audience will find the article interesting and useful. The translated article can be found <a href="http://dhr.ruc.edu.cn/EN/Y2023/V3/I1/24">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Translation"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m happy to share that my article “Infrastructuring digital humanities: On relational infrastructure and global reconfiguration of the field” published in Digital Scholarship in the Humanities has been translated into Chinese and released in the Digital Humanities Research journal.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Interviews published in Zenodo</title><link href="https://urszuladeger.github.io/blog/2023/interviews-published-in-zenodo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Interviews published in Zenodo"/><published>2023-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://urszuladeger.github.io/blog/2023/interviews-published-in-zenodo</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://urszuladeger.github.io/blog/2023/interviews-published-in-zenodo/"><![CDATA[<p>As part of my Marie Curie research, I conducted a set of interviews with members of King’s Digital Lab, management staff and researchers involved in the lab work. Discussions revolved around the institutional, research, and socio-technical infrastructure of King’s College London and King’s Digital Lab, the social practices of digital projects, the use of digital tools in everyday research practices and the challenges of conducting research with regard to the lab management, organisation, policies, and facilities. The transcripts of the interviews are available in Zenodo <a href="https://zenodo.org/record/7880810">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Data"/><category term="Interviews"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As part of my Marie Curie research, I conducted a set of interviews with members of King’s Digital Lab, management staff and researchers involved in the lab work. Discussions revolved around the institutional, research, and socio-technical infrastructure of King’s College London and King’s Digital Lab, the social practices of digital projects, the use of digital tools in everyday research practices and the challenges of conducting research with regard to the lab management, organisation, policies, and facilities. The transcripts of the interviews are available in Zenodo here.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New job at Wellcome</title><link href="https://urszuladeger.github.io/blog/2023/new-job-at-wellcome/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New job at Wellcome"/><published>2023-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://urszuladeger.github.io/blog/2023/new-job-at-wellcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://urszuladeger.github.io/blog/2023/new-job-at-wellcome/"><![CDATA[<p>The past few months have been quite busy leaving me with little time to update my website. So much has happened, and it’s been an incredible journey. First and foremost, I completed my Marie Curie fellowship at King’s College London, a truly great experience. I worked with wonderful people, learned a lot and produced a significant number of outputs that I’m proud of. I’m also thrilled to share that my book for Routledge has reached the production phase (more about it soon).</p> <p>But the most exciting news is that I’ve landed a permanent position at the prestigious <a href="https://wellcome.org">Wellcome Trust</a> as a Research Manager in the <a href="https://wellcome.org/what-we-do/discovery-research">Discovery Research programme</a>. I’m part of the Early Career and Career Development Researchers team that aims to support curiosity-driven research across diverse perspectives and contexts to transform understanding of life, health, and wellbeing.</p> <p>As a Research Manager, my goal is to foster a positive research culture, support researchers, and catalyse innovative, field-opening activities. A lot of projects have already been initiated and I’ll be sharing more details in due course. This is a great job and a workplace in the heart of London, at Euston Road. I couldn’t be happier with my new role!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The past few months have been quite busy leaving me with little time to update my website. So much has happened, and it’s been an incredible journey. First and foremost, I completed my Marie Curie fellowship at King’s College London, a truly great experience. I worked with wonderful people, learned a lot and produced a significant number of outputs that I’m proud of. I’m also thrilled to share that my book for Routledge has reached the production phase (more about it soon).]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My new paper in Convergence</title><link href="https://urszuladeger.github.io/2022/07/23/my-new-paper-in-convergence/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My new paper in Convergence"/><published>2022-07-23T16:54:21+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-23T16:54:21+00:00</updated><id>https://urszuladeger.github.io/2022/07/23/my-new-paper-in-convergence</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://urszuladeger.github.io/2022/07/23/my-new-paper-in-convergence/"><![CDATA[<p>My new open access article has been published in the <em>Convergence: The International Journal of Research into New Media Technologies</em>. Based on the ethnography of <a href="https://kdl.kcl.ac.uk">King’s Digital Lab</a>, I analyse Feasibility documents and propose a theoretical and methodological approach towards the study of documents in digital research production. The full article is available <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/13548565221111073">here</a>.</p> <p>Abstract:</p> <p>Documents have been increasingly recognised as important objects of investigation in Science and Technology Studies (STS); however, so far, much less attention has been given to the study of documents produced in Digital Humanities. The author proposes therefore to use the method of the ‘STS of documents’ and analyse Feasibility documents that aim to assess technical and design requirements based on research questions and to organise a project workflow. Drawing on the ethnography of King’s Digital Lab, the article investigates Feasibility documents produced by the lab within the Agile-based Software Development Lifecycle framework. The article aims to show that Feasibility documents (1) inform ethnographic work about lab workflow and management and in doing so, are able to capture the interconnectedness of work layers and practices; (2) enable an empirical analysis of digital research projects and the process of translation from research questions, to methods, to technical solutions; (3) are <em>critical structuring objects</em> that <em>structure</em> the research process and relationships between involved actors and <em>are structured by</em> local institutional strategies and decisions. The author conducts a ‘feasibility analysis’ that reveals the project management and development stages: the analytical process (the translation of research questions into technical solutions); the production process (the move from technical and design practices to research answers) and the infrastructure and management process (project workflow and sustainability solutions). Drawing on Agre’s critical technical practice and Digital Humanities’ theories of critical production, the article seeks to shift attention from end-product digital artefacts towards the complex process of their creation, which can unpack a range of social, technological and management issues. In doing so, it also aims to provide a methodological framework for the analysis of documents produced in Digital Humanities that have the potential to unearth new questions about the socio-technical nature of digital production.</p>]]></content><author><name>Urszula</name></author><category term="Digital culture"/><category term="Digital humanities"/><category term="Infrastructure"/><category term="Laboratory"/><category term="Open access"/><category term="Publications"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My new open access article has been published in the Convergence: The International Journal of Research into New Media Technologies. Based on the ethnography of King’s Digital Lab, I analyse Feasibility documents and propose a theoretical and methodological approach towards the study of documents in digital research production. The full article is available here.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My new piece in THE</title><link href="https://urszuladeger.github.io/2022/07/18/my-new-piece-in-the/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My new piece in THE"/><published>2022-07-18T10:47:23+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-18T10:47:23+00:00</updated><id>https://urszuladeger.github.io/2022/07/18/my-new-piece-in-the</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://urszuladeger.github.io/2022/07/18/my-new-piece-in-the/"><![CDATA[<p>I’m excited to share that my new piece, “Digital humanities needs equality between humanists and technicians”, has been published in <em>Times Higher Education</em>. It is about labour issues and recognition that are becoming increasingly salient in digital humanities labs. As I argue, introducing a fair publication policy, such <a href="https://www.kcl.ac.uk/governancezone/research/fair-publication-policy">as the one recently published by King’s</a>, is a step towards assuring that the work performed by research technicians and technology and skills specialists is acknowledged in research outputs. Recognition of contribution is a prerequisite for research production. Check it out <a href="https://www.timeshighereducation.com/blog/digital-humanities-needs-equality-between-humanists-and-technicians">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Urszula</name></author><category term="Digital culture"/><category term="Digital humanities"/><category term="Higher education"/><category term="Humanities"/><category term="Infrastructure"/><category term="Laboratory"/><category term="Publications"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m excited to share that my new piece, “Digital humanities needs equality between humanists and technicians”, has been published in Times Higher Education. It is about labour issues and recognition that are becoming increasingly salient in digital humanities labs. As I argue, introducing a fair publication policy, such as the one recently published by King’s, is a step towards assuring that the work performed by research technicians and technology and skills specialists is acknowledged in research outputs. Recognition of contribution is a prerequisite for research production. Check it out here.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My article reposted in DHLib</title><link href="https://urszuladeger.github.io/2022/07/18/my-article-reposted-in-dhlib/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My article reposted in DHLib"/><published>2022-07-18T10:44:59+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-18T10:44:59+00:00</updated><id>https://urszuladeger.github.io/2022/07/18/my-article-reposted-in-dhlib</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://urszuladeger.github.io/2022/07/18/my-article-reposted-in-dhlib/"><![CDATA[<p>Great to see that my article “The Laboratory Turn: Exploring Discourses, Landscapes, and Models of Humanities Labs” (<em>Digital Humanities Quarterly</em>, 2021:14.3) has been reposted on the Digital Humanities Program of Tsinghua University website. The team of this program established the first digital humanities journal (<em>Journal of Digital Humanities</em>, 《数字人文》, quarterly ) in the mainland of China in 2019. <a href="https://www.dhlib.cn/site/works/papers/type/cyberinfrastructure_paper/16318.html">Here</a> is the link.</p>]]></content><author><name>Urszula</name></author><category term="Digital humanities"/><category term="Humanities"/><category term="Infrastructure"/><category term="Laboratory"/><category term="Publications"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Great to see that my article “The Laboratory Turn: Exploring Discourses, Landscapes, and Models of Humanities Labs” (Digital Humanities Quarterly, 2021:14.3) has been reposted on the Digital Humanities Program of Tsinghua University website. The team of this program established the first digital humanities journal (Journal of Digital Humanities, 《数字人文》, quarterly ) in the mainland of China in 2019. Here is the link.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Critical Studies of a Tech Stack</title><link href="https://urszuladeger.github.io/2022/07/18/critical-studies-of-a-tech-stack/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Critical Studies of a Tech Stack"/><published>2022-07-18T10:42:07+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-18T10:42:07+00:00</updated><id>https://urszuladeger.github.io/2022/07/18/critical-studies-of-a-tech-stack</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://urszuladeger.github.io/2022/07/18/critical-studies-of-a-tech-stack/"><![CDATA[<p>In case you missed it, I published a <a href="https://dhinfra.org/336/critical-studies-of-a-tech-stack-a-technological-network-perspective/">new post</a> on my research website, <a href="https://dhinfra.org">dhinfra.org</a>, about critical studies of a tech stack based on the network visualisation method. It presents my forthcoming work co-authored with members of King’s Digital Lab which offers a contribution towards an understanding of the role of technologies in informing and shaping a lab culture. It aims to conceptualise and investigate a tech stack as a relational network of actors (universities, for-profit companies, non-profit organisations, communities, and individuals, e.g., research software engineers) engaged in mutual relationships and tensions – concerning open vs closed systems, the domination of corporate platforms, and local institutional policy. This in turn influences labs’ organisational decisions and socio-cultural settings. We intend to decode the complex relational assemblage of technologies, organisations, and cultures. In doing so, it aims to show how this network of associations configures the life and identity of digital humanities labs compromising across technological pragmatism – informed by stability and sustainability – and – ethos – driven by open and independent values. You can find the essay <a href="https://dhinfra.org/336/critical-studies-of-a-tech-stack-a-technological-network-perspective/">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Urszula</name></author><category term="Digital culture"/><category term="Digital humanities"/><category term="Infrastructure"/><category term="Laboratory"/><category term="Publications"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In case you missed it, I published a new post on my research website, dhinfra.org, about critical studies of a tech stack based on the network visualisation method. It presents my forthcoming work co-authored with members of King’s Digital Lab which offers a contribution towards an understanding of the role of technologies in informing and shaping a lab culture. It aims to conceptualise and investigate a tech stack as a relational network of actors (universities, for-profit companies, non-profit organisations, communities, and individuals, e.g., research software engineers) engaged in mutual relationships and tensions – concerning open vs closed systems, the domination of corporate platforms, and local institutional policy. This in turn influences labs’ organisational decisions and socio-cultural settings. We intend to decode the complex relational assemblage of technologies, organisations, and cultures. In doing so, it aims to show how this network of associations configures the life and identity of digital humanities labs compromising across technological pragmatism – informed by stability and sustainability – and – ethos – driven by open and independent values. You can find the essay here.]]></summary></entry></feed>